JACOB GIBSON

Marketing master student

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a marketing enthusiast and love to improve the whole organisation's performance by taking it to the next level with what we do in marketing every day. Thereby, I enjoy applying my knowledge in artificial intelligence (AI) to create an enhanced way of communicating with customers and improve their experience. The world of online marketing, social media, and project management especially thrill me. I would love to share this passion as part of your team in the future.

gibson.jacob.d@gmail.com

Mobile

07990 277384

Address

65 Ednaston Rd Nottingham NG7 2JF

SKILLS

Microsoft Office

Adobe Photoshop

IBM Watson

WordPress

Python and R

LANGUAGES

English
French

HOBBIES

Volleyball, design, outdoors and hiking, music and concerts, reading

EDUCATION

2:1 MSc Marketing

Nottingham Trent University

. 2020 - 2021

Key skills gained:

- Developing marketing campaigns and strategies in case studies
- Using AI / Machine Learning algorithms for personalised customer recommendations, prescriptive actions, and real-time analytics
- Using practical methods for conducting marketing research
- Gaining practical experience in a marketing consultancy experience project
- Building customer relationships
- · Developing digital businesses

2:1 BA (Hons) Business Management and Marketing

Nottingham Trent University ___ 2016 - 2020

Notable modules: Digital Customer Experience, Innovation in Marketing, Digital Entrepreneurship, Integrated Marketing Communications

Tapton Secondary School

___ 2014 - 2016

A-level passes in three subjects: Business Studies (A), Maths (B) and English Literature (B)

Tapton Secondary School

___ 2009 - 2014

11 GCSEs, grade A*-C including Maths and English

JACOB GIBSON

Marketing master student

WORK EXPERIENCE

Placement year in marketing division

ASOS - Online fashion retailer, London

2018 - 2019

- Implementing and using IBM's Watson AI for marketing
- Using Machine Learning algorithms and tools for marketing orchestration and real-time personalisation
- Writing creative copy and composing marketing communications
- Developing marketing campaigns and pitching them to the team
- Developing social media strategies and running accounts on platforms like Instagram, Facebook, and Twitter
- Optimising website performance using SEO
- Managing website content and e-mail marketing

3-month summer marketing internship

Drivy - Carsharing app provider, London

2017

- Planning marketing and communications campaigns
- Writing creative copy and composing marketing communications
- Managing website content with WordPress
- Creating and ordering advertisement materials
- Conducting market and competition research

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Online courses

- Neural Networks and Deep Learning (on coursera.org)
- Viral Marketing and How to Craft Contagious Content (on coursera.org)
- Social Media Marketing (on coursera.org)
- Python for Data Science (on edX.org)

Youth club volunteer

M8S Youth Club, Nottingham

2017 - today

Helping children with learning disabilities and supporting them in activities such as indoor and outdoor games, cooking, reading, and on outings like hiking trips, bowling or canoeing

REFERENCES

References will be provided upon request